

CV 2021

Technical Skills

PC - Windows

Adobe CC:

Illustrator Photoshop InDesign After Effects

CorelDraw

Microsoft Office:

Word Excel Powerpoint Outlook

Web Design:

Visual Studio Code Mobirise Adobe Muse HTML / CSS

Social Media:

Facebook Whatsapp Twitter Instagram

INTRODUCTION

At least 19 years' experience in graphic designing and 2 years' experience in newspaper print production process. I am a talented, ambitious and hardworking individual, with versatile skills and have experience working as part of a team and individually. Furthermore, I am able to handle multiple tasks on a daily basis and use a creative approach to problem solving. Other key strengths are that I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills. Strong attention to detail and ability to work effectively under pressure and meet tight deadlines.

Deliver all projects in a timely fashion. I am always on time for organized events, work-related or otherwise. Always highly enthused about my work and tasks ahead and understand the importance of being interactive and enjoy communicating with others for the benefit of the company and clients. I work with the team to provide imaginative solutions for customers. Co-workers rely on me to be on time. Even though I take my work seriously, I do have a good sense of humour. I have confidence in others and approach new challenges with an open mind.

EMPLOYMENT

Freelance Designer

Bloemfontein

1/6/2018 - Current

- Design for print and web, including logos and branding, apparel, brochures, leaflets, letterheads, adverts, signage, social media graphics, and more.
- Manage artwork preparation for print and web.
- Take / source and manipulate photographs.

CTP Operator

Paarlcoldset / Novus Holdings - Bloemfontein

1/4/2016 - 31/4/2018

- Managing the digital workflow processes of material received from clients.
- Delivery of quality plates on time and in full to the Pre-Press department.
- Carrying out routine maintenance procedures on all CTP equipment.
- Communicating and interacting with clients and other relevant production personnel in the organization.
- Perform troubleshooting and fault finding on Pre-Press machinery
- Adhere to all routine operator maintenance procedures on all Pre-Press equipment
- Ensure quality standards are adhered to, together with accurate record keeping according to expected standards.
- Agfa Arkitex workflow processes, Kodak Preps Imposition software, Graphic Design software applications and

Design Skills

Print Design: Broshures

Leaflets
Stationery
Signs
Posters
Logo's
Business Cards
Letterheads
Flyers

Digital Designs:

Web graphics
Social Media graphics
Digital adverts

Interests:

My design interests include typography, logo and identity design, vphotography, and digital adverts.

Outside of design I enjoy horror / sci-fi, crafts, coffee brewing, with an odd fondness for LEGO

References available on request.

knowledge of X-Rite measurement devices.

- Detail orientated whilst performing duties under extreme pressures.
- Quality Control Champion going through newspapers the press printed on quality, defects and record info in MIS. Complete day-2-day record on quality are kept and send to managers.
- Excellent communication, interpersonal and time management abilities.
- Experience of relevant Pre-Press quality control measures and procedures.

Graphic Designer / Team Leader

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

1/2/2000 - 31/3/2016

- Make up and lay out advertisements for the respective newspapers, supplements and booklets within the Volksblad-group
- Design promotional work for Volksblad group posters, logo's, banners, business cards, digital adverts, etc.
- Managing complete material received from clients.
- Retouching and deep etching of photos for editorial- and DTP-department.
- Co-ordinating workflow from ADS to desired departments in Pre-Press.
- Supported the sales reps with all aspects relating to graphic design
- Ensuring quality standards are kept in DTP department.
- Monitoring newspapers to ensure they meet their deadlines for print, accurate placement of all adverts and sending final pdf pages to CTP department for printing.
- Troubleshooting and fault finding if a guery comes through.
- Assisted when required to design print advertising and print material for all marketing communication project
- Communicating and interacting with relevant production personnel and managers within the organization.
- Team Leader to the Pre-Press department overseeing different apartments within Pre-Press and reported to General Manager.

Part time Graphic Designer

Foto & Video House - Bloemfontein

31/1/1999 - 1/12/1999

• Designed logo's, DVD covers and promotional work.

EDUCATION

Central University of Technology – FS National Diploma in Graphic Design 1995 – 1998

Louis Botha Technical High School – FS Metric / Senior Certificate 1990 – 1994

ACHIEVEMENTS

Volksblad / Media24 - Bloemfontein

- 2015 15 Years' Service Certificate
- 2015 Promoted to Team Leader for Pre-Press Department
- 2015 Graphic Designer of the Year Award
- 2010 10 Years' Service Certificate
- 2010 Graphic Designer of the Year Award
- 2004 Promoted to Head Designer



Johan Jacobs Bloemfontein, Free Sate

jjacobs064@gmail.com 071 675 5341 https://johanj76.github.io/mobirise/index.html

Thank you!

If you would like to see more of my work, please visit https://johanj76.github.io/mobirise/index.html